<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>carsten.dev</title><description>carsten.dev</description><link>https://carsten.dev</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:33:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:33:38 +0200</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://carsten.dev/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://carsten.dev/career/365farmnet</guid><title>365FarmNet</title><description></description><link>https://carsten.dev/career/365farmnet</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:33:37 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>365FarmNet</strong></h1><h3>since 2021</h3><p>Right from the start, I've been responsible for crafting new features for the Active App, starting with version 2.1.0. Currently, I'm using the opportunity to enhance my skills in <strong>SwiftUI</strong>, employing a combination of <strong>MVVM</strong>, <strong>Clean Architecture</strong>, and <strong>Reactive Programming</strong>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://carsten.dev/me/Work</guid><title>Ich als Kollege</title><description></description><link>https://carsten.dev/me/Work</link><pubDate>Mon, 1 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Ich als Kollege</h1><p>Damit ihr nicht die Katze im Sack kauft, vorab noch einige Infos zur mir als Kollege:</p><p>Ich bin ein offener Mensch der sagt was er denkt, aber auch weiß wann es nicht angebracht ist. Ich bin bei jedem Thema offen für eine Diskussion. Ich vertete gerne meinen Standpunkt, aber beharre nicht darauf und lasse mich von anderen Meinungen überzeugen. Ebenso weiß ich auch wann es nicht mehr lohnt zu diskutieren bzw. eine Diskussion beendet ist.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://carsten.dev/career/Check24</guid><title>Check24 Möbel</title><description></description><link>https://carsten.dev/career/Check24</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Check24 Möbel</strong></h1><h3>May 2020 - Nov 2020</h3><p>Given the early stage of the developed app, I established the <strong>MVVM</strong> architecture as the foundation. Collaborating with the team, we refactored existing features to align with MVVM principles. My significant contribution included leading the development of the startup, product detail, and category screens. With the objective of remaining independent of third-party libraries, we collectively implemented a custom <strong>Reactive Programming</strong> solution within the team.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://carsten.dev/career/iconmobile</guid><title>iconmobile</title><description></description><link>https://carsten.dev/career/iconmobile</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>iconmobile</strong></h1><h3>May 2014 - May 2020</h3><p>During my time as a student worker and in a full-time role, I contributed to various projects and prototype developments, conducted thorough research on diverse topics, and engaged in comprehensive app benchmarking. While working on the development of new features across different projects, I began using <strong>Swift from version 1.0</strong> onward. I gained hands-on experience with various architectural paradigms, although most apps during that period primarily utilized either <strong>MVC</strong>, a customized MVC variant, or <strong>MVVM</strong>.</p><h3></h3><p>The most significant milestone in my career at iconmobile was proving myself in the role of Lead in a client project, where, as a team, we successfully achieved our project goals.</p><h3></h3><p>Some of the particularly exciting projects I had the opportunity to work on include:</p><ul><li>Oral-B versions 3.0 to 5.1</li><li>Oral-B Smart Mirror Prototype</li><li>We Park</li><li>Henkel SalonLab</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://carsten.dev/me/Privat</guid><title>What I do outside of work</title><description></description><link>https://carsten.dev/me/Privat</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>What I do outside of work</strong></h1><p>Like many other teenagers of the 2000s, I was deeply interested in video games, trading cards, computers, the internet, and, of course, television and movies. Today, these interests, especially those concerning computers, the internet, and video games, continue to be a part of my life. During my gaming sessions, I spend a lot of time on the internet, constantly experimenting with new things. It all started with creating a simple website. After that, I developed small programs and scripts that helped me with various tasks on my PC. With my entry into the world of software development, I found my passion as an iOS developer (obviously 😉).</p><h3></h3><p>In addition to software development, I also have hobbies that I practice to varying degrees of proficiency, such as graphic design, creating 3D models for my 3D printer, baking muffins and cakes, playing Yo-Yo, and binge-watching every single episode of Doctor Who. Outside my four walls, I enjoy going bouldering with friends, occasionally strolling through flea markets, and taking beach walks in my hometown.</p><h3></h3><p>Furthermore, I've recently become fascinated by everything related to AI. In addition to experimenting with image generation, I plan to train my own LLM for a personal project, which can then be used as a chatbot in an app. Currently, I have several other small projects in the pipeline.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://carsten.dev/me/Beuth</guid><title>Master of Science</title><description></description><link>https://carsten.dev/me/Beuth</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Master of Science</strong></h1><h3>March 2017</h3><p>The focus of my master's thesis was on exploiting the error correction capabilities of QR codes. Leveraging the acquired knowledge, I developed a library for Android and iOS, enabling users to personalize the black modules of a QR code with their images. This involved intentionally introducing errors into the QR code to optimize the representation of the embedded image. I successfully completed my master's degree study at Beuth University of Applied Sciences in Berlin with an overall grade of "<strong>very good</strong>".</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>